Travis Gottwaldt

travis@gottwaldt.com
https://www.linkedin.com/in/travisgottwaldt
https://gottwaldt.com

Summary

Passionate Cyber Security Analyst with experience in Vulnerability Management, Risk Assessment, and Threat Hunting. Collaborates with engineers to reduce the attack surface and enhance the security of the organization and work with vendors to help implement and test new software tools. Skilled in remote troubleshooting of workstations and utilizing ticketing systems. Competed in the Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition for 2 years as a firewall administrator on Palo Alto firewalls, achieving 3rd place in 2023 and 1st place in 2024 in Minnesota, where we moved on to the regionals in Chicago and placed 5th. I am dedicated to staying current with the latest cyber trends through attending webinars and conferences, while spreading cybersecurity awareness.

Work Experience

Grand Casino
Cyber Security Analyst
June 2024 to Present

- Vulnerability Management and Risk Assessment of organizations assets, working with engineers to reduce the attack surface and enhance security.
- Use SIEM tools to monitor and detect potential security incidents.
- Work with consultants to implement phishing simulation campaigns and set up user awareness training.
- Utilize RMM software to deploy patches and remotely troubleshoot end users' workstations.

Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition Firewall Administrator November 2022 to March 2024

- Configured Palo Alto firewalls with multiple subnets and implemented port/application-based security policies across segmented zones to improve security.
- Identified misconfigurations and vulnerable services, remediating and securing those vulnerabilities.
- Monitored traffic logs for suspicious activity, working as a team with other administrators to mitigate threats.

• Documented firewall configurations, policies, and procedures and ensured compliance with competition rules.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Cyber Security and Information Assurance Western Governors University, Salt Lake City UT October 2024 - Current

Associate of Applied Science in Cyber Security
Pine Technical and Community College, Pine City MN
August 2022 - May 2024
Phi Theta Kappa Honors Society

<u>Awards</u>

- 2024 Midwest Regional Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition 5th Place
- 2024 Minnesota Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition 1st Place
- 2023 Minnesota Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition 3rd Place

Certifications

- A+
- Network+
- Security+